

amaniyote@gmail.com (+233) 531952530 (+91) 9846200879 [WhatsApp] Accra, Ghana

# **Professional Summary**

A Qualified IT Professional with 2 years of experience as a ServiceNow Developer and Administrator.

Experience in Configuring Applications using ServiceNow tool, used in ITIL Management.

Strong understanding of ITIL V3.

Deep functional and technical knowledge of the ServiceNow platform as well as experience in delivering medium to large-scale ServiceNow implementations.

## **Work Experience**

#### Senior System Engineer, ServiceNow Developer

Infosys Limited

Jun 2021 - April 2023 Pune, India

- Implemented, documented and maintained the Service-Now platform to meet specific business needs to support ITIL and business processes.
- Worked with a Telecom giant 'Inmarsat Plc', one of the world's leading Satellite Service Provider under its fully edged E2E order Placement and Provisioning Application: Inmarsat Service Delivery Platform.
- Entitled the primary role of Inventory Manager and Subject Matter Expert of 'Service Resource Inventory & Logical Resource Management', which are custom applications built on PaaS platform ServiceNow.
- Designed, planned and developed strategic solutions for client requirements and needs for successive sprint Releases whilst playing the role of Lead Developer, to resolve proactive production issues.
- Responsibilities: Customized UI Appearance for Custom Application which is simple, intuitive and easy to use.
- Configuration of Email Notification and Alerts to notify users about specific activities in the custom applications.
- Responsible for maintaining and growing data held within ServiceNow Custom Applications.
- Administer the tools and enhanced requests by JavaScript Involved Agile methodology for daily SCRUM sessions and project tracking status.
- Worked on the defects post upgrade and fixed the defects.
- Utilized Java Scripting in Archival, Business Rules, Client scripts, UI Policies, Import-Export and UI Actions to deliver solutions that automate and audit business processes.
- To customize the instance as per Business needs.
- Responsible for access control, security, minor enhancements such as form editing.
- Responsible for gathering requirements and customizing Business Service Catalogs for organization from the scratch.
- Created and Maintained foundation data User Accounts, Roles, Approvers, Support Groups, Sites, Production Categorizations, and Templates Involved in providing the design solution, technical methodologies and processes solution to meet the customer requirements.

- Worked on Batch API which can process a single request containing multiple REST API calls and this helped to reduce the cutover time for migration to 60%.
- Worked on ServiceNow Upgrade from Quebec to San Diego
- Handled Client Calls & effective communication with Product Owners

## **System Engineer Trainee**

Infosys Limited Jan 2021 - May 2021 Mysore, India

- Completed Infosys Foundation Programme for System Engineer Trainee.
- Training Included Basic Java Programming, SQL (Relational Database Management Systems), Full Stack Java Development (Angular) and a Capstone Project.

#### **Skills**

JavaScript Change Management. Scripted REST API
Configuration & Asset

Management

Python Data Science MySQL Data Analytics

Tableau HTML CSS Flask

Agile Methodologies

## **Education**

# **Certified Specialist in Data Science & Analytics**

ICT Academy of Kerala Aug 2022 - Jan 2023 Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala

**B-Tech Electrical & Electronics Engineering** 

LBS College Of Engineering Aug 2016 - Jun 2020 Kasaragod, Kerala

**Plus Two** 

Govt Girls HSS, Perinthalmanna Aug 2013 - Mar 2015 Perinthalmanna

## **Achievements**

### **Awards & Appreciations**

• Client Appreciation in effective delivery of Application

- Infosys Insta Rise Awards recommended by DU Head-23 June '22
- Infosys Insta Rise Awards recommended by Senior Project Manager- 14 Sep '22
- Infosys Insta Rise Awards recommended by Project Manager- 26 Dec '22
- Presented paper in Virtual International Conference on Power Initiatives (ICPI)-2020 on MFC based Air Quality Sensing conducted by IEEE SB of K Ramakrishnan College of Engineering, Tiruchirappalli